go on, change your name. No, not permanently or legally. But get
comfortable with saying your own name differently than you have for your entire
life. It may feel weird, unreal, surreal, or just plain dumb, but it's an invaluable
mental exercise. Every time I landed in a new country, my first order of business
was to find out who I was, or at least how my name was pronounced. I went from
Madrid, Me llamo Anita, to Paris, Je m 'appelle Annie, to Tokyo, Watashi wa Annie
desu. Drop the baggage. For a lot of people, the American accent comes with a
lot of emotional baggage. Americans are loud, emotionally immature,
unsophisticated. It may be conflicting for an educated sophisticate such as yourself
to work towards actually sounding like this. But you need to fit in and be
understood, so drop off the baggage. Just focus on the pure sounds." Emotional
Investment in Particular Sounds A man with a distinctly Spanish accent had trouble
distinguishing iPod from iPad. He learned the ass sound for iPad, but didn't
extrapolate that sound to other words such as cat, laugh, or dance. It would be
natural to think that he simply didn't know where to use it. But surprisingly,
when asked why he didn't use the ass sound, he laughingly responded, Some
people have a strong identification with their pronunciation, considering it part
of their identity or personal brand. They may reject a single sound or the entire
accent. Unless the change wells from within, the accent won't take root and
become a true part of them.